worldpay.us 2015-10-22

# Privacy Policy US | Worldpay

### Online Privacy Statement

We respect and value your privacy. Our Online Privacy Statement (“Privacy Statement”) describes and applies to the information we collect from you when you visit this website (“Website”). The terms “we,” “our,” and “us” in this Privacy Statement refer to Worldpay US, Inc. Our Privacy Statement generally describes how we collect, share, use, and protect your information.

### 1\. Information That We Collect

When you visit our Website, we receive and collect certain information about you. The information that we receive and collect depends in part on what you do when you visit our Website. You may be able to improve your experience on our Website when you tell us who you are – for example, by signing up for e-mail or newsletters, applying for products, making inquiries, or requesting further information about a product or service.

Some of the information you may submit is personally identifiable information, but much of it is not. Personally identifiable information is information that identifies a particular person. Examples include your name, phone number, address, and social security number. It is possible to browse our Website without actively submitting any personally identifiable information.

We or our third-party service providers may use this information for a number of purposes, for example, to better service your requests and/or inquiries, monitor Website usage and/or performance, improve the customer experience of our Website, ensure technological compatibility with your computer, protect against fraud or identity theft, or conduct aggregate analyses on usage patterns.

### Automatically Collected Information

Every time you visit a website, some information is automatically collected from you. For example, this information may include some or all of the following items: your computer’s Internet protocol (IP) address and/or domain; type and version of Internet browser software and operating system you use; date, time, and duration of your Website access; specific pages, buttons, images, videos, links, or forms that you access while visiting the Website; and demographic information concerning the country of origin of your computer and the language(s) used by it.

### Information Collected via Cookies and Other Similar Technology

“Cookies” are small text files that are placed on your computer to distinguish you from other visitors to our Website. The use of cookies is a standard practice among websites to collect or track information about your activities while using the website. We or our third-party service providers may place cookies or similar files on your hard drive for many of the reasons listed above while visiting our Website. Most people do not know that cookies are being placed on their computers when they visit websites because browsers are typically set to accept cookies. You can choose to have your browser warn you every time a cookie is being sent to you or you can choose not to accept cookies. You can also delete cookies from your computer at any time. If you refuse cookies, the functionality of our Website may be impacted or become non-functional.

In addition to using cookies, we or our third-party service providers may also use similar technologies to track users’ interactions with our Website. Some of these technologies include web beacons (transparent graphical images placed on a website) and flash objects.

We may use these technologies on our Website to verify your identity, remember personal settings including your preferences, to offer you additional options or enhance your online experience, and to improve our products and services. We may also use them for marketing site personalization, and tracking of online applications and programs and/or track the effectiveness of advertisements for our products and services, referred to as banner ads, that we may place on our Website or other linked and/or partner websites. Cookies used for tracking advertising effectiveness do not collect personally identifiable information. In order to better serve you, some of these technologies allow us the ability to view your past interactions with our Websites for customer service, troubleshooting, risk analysis and fraud detection, as well as other related purposes.

### 2\. Information You Choose to Submit

For most of the browsing on our Website, we neither require nor collect personally identifiable information. You can browse our Website and take as much time as you want to review our services without having to submit such information.

### 3\. E-Mail Communications

Forms of communication such as e-mail, text messaging, our Website Contact Us, or other forms of electronic communication are inherently insecure. Please refrain from submitting sensitive personal information (such as account number, social security number, or credit card account number) via e-mail or similar method of communication.

When you send an e-mail to us, you are communicating with us electronically and consent to receive reply communications from us or our providers electronically. We may retain the content of the e-mail, your e-mail address, and our response in order to better service your needs or for legal and regulatory reasons.

### 4\. Personal Information on Children

We respect the privacy of your children and encourage all parents to supervise their children’s computer usage. We do not knowingly collect or retain personal information from children under the age of thirteen. We advise all visitors to our Website under the age of 13 not to disclose or provide any personally identifiable information on our Website. To learn more about the Children’s Online Privacy Protect Act (COPPA) please visit the Federal Trade Commission’s website at [_http://www.business.ftc.gov/privacy-and-security/children's-privacy_](http://www.business.ftc.gov/privacy-and-security/children's-privacy).

### 5\. Third Party Websites

Our Website may contain links to third-party websites. These links and pointers to third-party websites are not part of our Website. We do not make any representations or warranties regarding these third-party websites. We are not responsible for any losses or damages in connection with the information, security, privacy practices, availability, content or accuracy of materials of such third-party websites. These third-party websites might have privacy policies different from us and third-party websites may provide less privacy and/or security than our Website. We encourage you to review the privacy and security policies of all third-party websites before you share any personally identifiable information.

### 6\. Additional Uses or Sharing of Your Information

In addition to those methods discussed in this Privacy Statement, we may use and share your information, including personally identifiable information, without limitation, in the following manner:

  * In response to judicial or other governmental subpoenas, warrants and court orders served on us in accordance with their terms, or as otherwise required by applicable law;
  * To comply with legal, regulatory or administrative requirements of governmental authorities;
  * To protect our rights or property, protect our legitimate business interests, to enforce the provisions of our terms or policies, in cases of customer fraud/disputes, and/or to prevent harm to you or others;
  * To protect or defend us, our subsidiaries, affiliates, or parent company and any of their officers, directors, employees, agents, contractors and partners, in connection with any legal action, claim or dispute;
  * As disclosed in other applicable policies, terms of use, or other agreements; or
  * As permitted or required by law or as authorized by you.

### 7\. Online Security

We maintain security standards that are designed to protect your information as it is transmitted from your computer to our network. This technology is called Secure Socket Layer (SSL). SSL is the leading security protocol for data transfer on the Internet and helps to protect the safety and confidentiality of your online banking information.

### 8\. How to Protect Your Personally Identifiable Information

You have a role in helping us by safeguarding your information from others. You have several options when deciding how you can best protect your personally identifiable information. One option is simply not to volunteer it. The Federal Trade Commission’s websites ([ _www.ftc.gov_](http://www.ftc.gov/), [_www.ftc.gov/idtheft_](http://www.ftc.gov/idtheft), and [_www.onguardonline.gov_](http://www.onguardonline.gov/)) offer useful information about how to protect your personally identifiable information.

### 9\. Suspicious E-Mail

We will never e-mail you to request personal information over the Internet or by any other means. Help protect yourself against online fraud – if you suspect that an unsolicited e-mail is fraudulent, please contact us.

### 10\. Notice to Persons Accessing this Website Outside the United States

If you reside outside the U.S., any information you provide to us on our Website will be transferred out of your country and into the U.S. If you do not want your personally identifiable information to leave your country, do not provide the information to us. By providing personally identifiable information to us, you explicitly consent to the transfer of your information to the U.S.

### 11\. Changes to our Online Privacy Statement

Please note that we will periodically make changes to our Privacy Statement. It is your responsibility to review this Privacy Statement frequently and remain informed about any changes to it, so we encourage you to visit this page often. Your continued use of our Website constitutes your acceptance of any amendments to and the most recent versions of this Privacy Statement.

### 12\. Questions or Comments

If you have any questions or comments concerning our Privacy Statement please let us know by emailing [_privacy@worldpay.us_](mailto:privacy@worldpay.us).

### PRINTING INSTRUCTIONS

For a copy of this document, use the print command on your web browser.

_**This Privacy Statement was last updated on: July 1, 2012**_
